Guide to the Minnie Fisher Cunningham: The McArthur-Smith Research Papers
University of Houston Libraries
Minnie Fisher Cunningham: The McArthur-Smith Research Papers
1914-1999
1920-1944
02/2013-005
McArthur, Judith N.; Smith, Harold L.
3.00 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
This collection consists of the research materials of Drs. Judith McArthur and Harold Smith. Included are copies of materials held at other institutions as well as the authors’ notes. The collection is divided into six series: Minnie Fisher Cunningham, People, Conventions/Conferences, Organizations/Committees, Issues, and Photographic Material. All materials relate to Minnie and her various efforts across differing fields of interest. The bulk of the papers consist of correspondence between Minnie and individuals and organizations. The series is organized thematically and alphabetically.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
League of Women Voters of Houston; National American Woman Suffrage Association; Texas Equal Suffrage Association
Genre/Form of Material:
Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Photographs; Records (documents); Speeches (documents)
Personal Name:
Cunningham, Minnie Fisher, 1882-1964
Topical Term:
Suffragists -- Texas; Women -- Political activity -- Texas; Women -- Suffrage -- Texas
Acquisition Information:
Donated
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research
Related Materials:
Minnie Fisher Cunningham Papers (http://archon.lib.uh.edu/index.php?p=collections/controlcard&id=235)
Minnie Fisher Cunningham Papers digital collection (http://digital.lib.uh.edu/collection/p15195coll33)
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of the research materials of Drs. Judith McArthur and Harold Smith. Included are copies of materials held at other institutions as well as the authors’ notes. The collection is divided into six series: Minnie Fisher Cunningham, People, Conventions/Conferences, Organizations/Committees, Issues, and Photographic Material. All materials relate to Minnie and her various efforts across differing fields of interest. The bulk of the papers consist of correspondence between Minnie and individuals and organizations. The series is organized thematically and alphabetically.
Note: A significant portion of the materials included in the collection are photocopies or reprints acquired from institutions other than the University of Houston and as such the holding institution must be cited where applicable.
Detailed List of Contents
- Minnie Fisher Cunningham, id148566
  - Personal, id148567
    - 1920s, id148615 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1930s, id148616 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bibliography, id148617 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - General Biography, id148618 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Gubernatorial Campaign, 1944; id148619 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Marriage, id148620 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Papers, id148621 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Primary Sources, id148622 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Primary Sources, id148623 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - League of Women Voters, id148568
    - Articles, id148625 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Congressional, id148626 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Cunningham In, id148627 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Edwards, Mary Stuart, id148628 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Elections, id148629 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Interracial Cooperation 1920s, id148630 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Inventories, id148631 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - National Headquarters, id148632 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Organization, id148633 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Organizational, id148634 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Parties/Partisanship, id148635 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Texas, id148636 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Senate Race, id148569
    - 1928, id148638 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Anti-Smith Democrats, id148639 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Candidates, id148640 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Clippings, id148641 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Finances (Dorothy K. Brown), id148642 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Issues, id148643 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Organization/Publicity, id148644 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Post-Mortem, id148645 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- People, id148570
  - Adams, Mark, id148647 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Barry, Maggie W., id148648 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Brown, Dorothy K., id148649 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Carter, Margaret, id148650 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Catt, Carrie Chapman, id148651 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Collier, Lillian, id148652 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Creekmore, Faith, id148653 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Cunningham, B.J., id148654 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Dobie, J. Frank, id148655 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Edwards, India, id148656 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Ellis, Coswell, id148657 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Garcia, Hector, id148658 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Goodman, Adele, id148659 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Graham, Frank, id148660 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Granbery, John, id148661 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Grimmet, Beulah, id148662 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Hall, Winter, id148663 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Hardeman, D.B., id148664 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Hill, Kate Adele, id148665 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Hogg, Louisa Pearson, id148666 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Highes, Sarah T., id148667 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., id148668 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Kennedy, John F., id148669 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Lathrop, Julia, id148670 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Mason, Lucy, id148671 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - McAllister, Dorothy, id148672 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - McCallum, Jane, id148673 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Mitchell, Stephen, id148674 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Newell, Blair Emily, id148675 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Parten, J.R., id148676 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Patman, Wright, id148677 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Rainey, Homer, id148678 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Randolph, Frankie Carter, id148679 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Rayburn, Sam, id148680 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Sherwin, Belle, id148681 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Stevenson, Adlai, id148682 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Truman, Harry, id148683 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Wallace, Henry A., id148684 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Williams, Aubrey, id148685 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Wright, Jim, id148686 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Conventions/Conferences, id148571
  - Congressmen and 1956 Democratic Convention, id148688 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Get Out the Vote, 1924; id148689 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Political Party Convention, 1924; id148690 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Pan American Conference, 1922; id148691 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Rural-Urban Conferences, id148692 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Southern Conference for Human Welfare, id148693 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Texas Social & Legislative Conference, id148694 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - White House Conference on Women in Post War Policy Making, 1944; id148695 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Organizations/Committees, id148572
  - Agriculture Adjustment Administration, id148697 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Americans for Democratic Action, id148698 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Civil Service Commission, 1925; id148699 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Consumer Division, National Advisory Commission, id148734 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Democratic Advisory Council, id148735 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Eleanor Roosevelt and Democratic National Committee, id148736 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation, id148737 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Federation of Women's Clubs, id148738 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - General Federation of Women's Clubs, id148739 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - National Archives, id148740 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - National Committee to Defeat the Unequal Rights Amendment, id148741 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - National Defense Advisory Commission, id148742 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - National YWCA, id148743 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - People's Legislative Committee, id148744 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - People's Library Movement for Texas, id148745 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Rice University Unpublished Paper, March 18, 1999; id148746 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Roosevelt Library, id148747 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Rosenburg Library-Galveston, id148748 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Sam Houston State University, id148749 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - State Democrat Executive Committee, id148750 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - State Observer, id148751 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Texas AFL-CIO, id148752 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Texas A&M Extension Service, 1914-1970; id148753 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Texas Democratic Party, id148754 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Texas Women's State Committee, id148755 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Texas Federation News, id148756 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Texas Federation of Women's Clubs, id148757 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Texas Observer, id148758 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - U.S. Department of Agriculture, id148759 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Walker County, id148760 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Women's Committee for Educational Freedom, id148761 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Women's Committee on Economic Policy for Texas, id148762 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Women's Division-Democratic National Convention, id148763 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Women's Joint Congressional Committee, id148764 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Women's National Democrat Club, id148765 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Issues, id148573
  - 1920s, id148767 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - 1944, id148768 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - 1950s, id148769 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Agriculture, id148770 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Agriculture Post-1945, id148771 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Census/Family, id148772 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Civil Rights/Integration, id148773 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Equal Rights/FDR, id148774 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Interracialism, id148775 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - National Defense, id148776 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Nutrition and Food Policy, id148777 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Politics-Texas, id148778 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Post-1945, id148779 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Post-Suffrage, id148780 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Post-Suffrage Politics, id148781 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Religion, id148782 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Voting 1920s, id148783 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Washington, D.C., id148784 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Photographic Material, id148574
  - Photographic Reprints, id148786 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Book Photographs, id148787 (Box 3, Folder 52)